<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>org.buhocms.BuhoCMS</id>
  <name>BuhoCMS</name>
  <summary>A local CMS for static site generators</summary>
  <developer_name>iakmds</developer_name>
  
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.0" />
  
  <url type="homepage">https://buhocms.org</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/iakmds/buhocms/issues</url>
  <url type="translate">https://github.com/iakmds/buhocms/#translating</url>
	
  <description>
    <p>
      BuhoCMS is a local Content Management System for static site generators.
    </p>
    <p>
      See BuhoCMS as a GUI for static site generators. Easily create or open a website, choose your theme and add your first posts. With BuhoCMS, adding and editing content is as easy as a few clicks. No more terminal commands, folder hunting or manual Front matter edits!
    </p>
    <ul>
        <li>SSGs supported: Hugo, Jekyll, 11ty</li>
        <li>Create or open a site</li>
        <li>Install themes for your site</li>
        <li>Add new posts and edit your Markdown content and Front matter with ease</li>
        <li>Edit content: Use the Markdown toolbar for quickly adding styles</li>
        <li>Markdown preview: Use the Markdown viewer to check your syntax</li>
        <li>Front matter: Graphical User Interface (GUI) for each field like a Text field, Switch, Date picker, Tag editor, and more</li>
        <li>Switch between GUI and raw text mode</li>
        <li>Start, open and stop your local server with a click</li>
        <li>Build your final website and open its folder</li>
        <li>Privacy: BuhoCMS is a local program with no internet connection required – no ads, no tracking</li>
        <li>Free and open source: Licensed under the GPLv3</li>
        <li>Themes: Material Design with multiple color themes, both light and dark</li>
        <li>Fully responsive</li>
        <li>Multiple languages supported – Contribute translating your language!</li>
        <li>...and many more features planned</li>
    </ul>
  </description>
  
  <launchable type="desktop-id">org.buhocms.BuhoCMS.desktop</launchable>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/iakmds/buhocms/master/.github/screenshot1.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/iakmds/buhocms/master/.github/screenshot2.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/iakmds/buhocms/master/.github/screenshot3.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/iakmds/buhocms/master/.github/screenshot4.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <releases>
    <release version="0.9.0" date="2023-05-19">
      <description>
        <p>Release 0.9.0 of BuhoCMS</p>
        <ul>
	       <li>New: Set custom executable paths for a static site generator</li>
          <li>UI: Fix "close tab" button position on hover</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.8.0" date="2023-05-15">
      <description>
        <p>Release 0.8.0 of BuhoCMS</p>
        <ul>
	       <li>New: Change theme to Material 3</li>
          <li>Fix: Add correct folder path on right click menu when creating new folder</li>
          <li>UX: Show progress indicator when creating website</li>
          <li>UX: Improve error notice when having a front matter duplicate</li>
          <li>UX: Do not show custom duplicate file dialog when exporting the preferences, use native instead</li>
          <li>UI: Text field/Markdown viewer ratio to 3/2 from 1/2</li>
          <li>UI: Use minimum width in the "Add file" and "Add folder" dialog</li>
          <li>Code: Use int for navigation and file navigation bar width instead of double</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.7.1" date="2023-05-04">
      <description>
        <p>Release 0.7.1 of BuhoCMS</p>
        <ul>
	       <li>Fix: Opening files inside folders not working</li>
          <li>Fix: Not creating Hugo post correctly inside folders</li>
          <li>Fix: If existent in front matter, use single/double quotes when saving value</li>
          <li>Localization: Fix title in terminal output window not updating</li>
          <li>Various other improvements, bug fixes and localization changes</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.7.0" date="2023-05-03">
      <description>
        <p>Release 0.7.0 of BuhoCMS</p>
        <ul>
	       <li>New: Add 11ty support</li>
          <li>New: Change SSG specific content folder inside BuhoCMS</li>
          <li>New: Add editing and settings page buttons to the menu bar</li>
          <li>Fix: Add front matter when having 0 entries</li>
          <li>Various other improvements, bug fixes and localization changes</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.6.2" date="2023-04-24">
      <description>
        <p>Release 0.6.2 of BuhoCMS</p>
        <ul>
	       <li>Fix: Exception when having a multiline value in front matter</li>
          <li>Other: Improved front matter saving logic</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.6.1" date="2023-04-19">
      <description>
        <p>Release 0.6.1 of BuhoCMS</p>
        <ul>
	       <li>Fix: Open website showing grey screen</li>
          <li>Fix: Importing preferences not updating navigation bars</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.6.0" date="2023-04-12">
      <description>
        <p>Release 0.6.0 of BuhoCMS</p>
        <ul>
	       <li>FLATPAK: The Hugo and Git executables will be removed from the Flatpak. This results in a smaller app size, but you will need to give permission to run the executables on your host system via: flatpak --user override org.buhocms.BuhoCMS --talk-name=org.freedesktop.Flatpak</li>
          <li>Jekyll is now supported! You can now choose between Hugo and Jekyll</li>
          <li>Fix changing language not updating the settings page</li>
          <li>Set newly created website as most recent website</li>
          <li>Remove empty space between menu bar and submenus</li>
          <li>Make Snackbar text selectable</li>
          <li>Various other improvements, bug fixes and localization changes</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.5.0" date="2023-03-23">
      <description>
        <p>Release 0.5.0 of BuhoCMS</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Markdown Toolbar: Now supporting shortcuts</li>
	      <li>Do not check for unsaved file when changing folder</li>
          <li>Set Hugo theme based on current config, not app preferences</li>
          <li>Parse front matter as yaml instead of custom parsing</li>
          <li>Improve theme legibility</li>
          <li>Various bug fixes and localization improvements</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.4.0" date="2023-03-14">
      <description>
        <p>Release 0.4.0 of BuhoCMS</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Ability to resize the text field in the editing page up and down</li>
	      <li>Use 2/3 for text field, 1/3 for markdown preview</li>
          <li>Various bug fixes and localization improvements</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.0" date="2023-03-08">
      <description>
        <p>Release 0.3.0 of BuhoCMS</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Auto-Detect Front matter button - a great help for sites with lots of Front matter types</li>
          <li>Recently opened websites list when opening a site</li>
          <li>Terminal output button to view all command logs</li>
          <li>Add Chinese translation</li>
          <li>Various bug fixes and localization improvements</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.2.0" date="2023-02-27">
      <description>
        <p>Release 0.2.0 of BuhoCMS</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Custom Hugo Flags are now supported when (i) starting a Hugo server, (ii) building a Hugo site, (iii) creating a new post, (iv) creating a new Hugo site</li>
          <li>Switch between Front matter GUI/Text mode with a new button</li>
          <li>Tags GUI: Add a submit button on the right side</li>
          <li>Various bug fixes and localization improvements</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.0" date="2023-02-09">
      <description>
        <p>Initial release of BuhoCMS</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Learn about all the features on the Homepage!</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
